Mahima Bhutani ui/ux designer

I have utmost fascination for different human perceptions. I have realised that I want to influence and gratify these humanly experiences with harmonious design. Thus, I have devoted myself to enhacing user experience via my work. Portfolio www.bhutani.design

Mail mahima@bhutani.design

Call +358 40 6106531

Linkedin linkedin.com/in/mahimabhutani

EXPERIENCE

Jan 2020 - Present

UI/UX Designer

FA Solutions Oy, Helsinki, Finland

- Created a design system which includes a new theme and a component library.
- Researched and designed a new web application. Successfully mapping client requirements, managing developer handoff and conducting usability testing.
- Conducted UX reviews for various new functionalities to provide customers with better user experience.

2017 - Present

UI/UX Designer

Freelancer

Designed various mobile apps and web applications for multiple companies.

Jan 2019 - Jan 2020

UI/UX Designer

Scania CV, Södertäjle, Sweden

- Analysed and tested products while maintaining user-centric design approach.
- Researched and designed a dashboard to facilitate coordination among different teams. It resulted in higher task-tracking efficiency due to assisted decision making.

Nov 2015 - June 2017

Integration Engineer

Ericsson

Responsible for maintenance of Order Management system for Telecom operators which enables management of customer data like billing, revenue, personal information etc.

EDUCATION

Aug 2017 - Jul 2019

M.Sc. Human Computer Interaction and Design

KTH Royal Institute of Technology, Sweden

Master Thesis: Evaluating User Experience while retrieving information via Dashboard.

Jul 2011 - May 2015

B.Tech. Computer Science

Jaypee University of engineering and Technology, India

Major Project: Enhancing security in Virtual Environment.

SKILLS

Design

Interaction Design, Mobile & Web UI Design, Wireframing & Mockups, Design system (Components & Theming)

Research methods

Data & Task Analysis; Persona, Storyboarding, Usability Testing, Rapid Prototyping, A/B testing, User Interviews

Prototyping Tools

Sketch, Adobe XD, Invision, Figma

Soft Skills

Market Research, Presentation Skills, Financial Evaluation, Team Management

Front end development

HTML, CSS, JavaScript